<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The decree for tythes, to bee payde in London Anno M.D.LXXX.</title>
            <author>City of London (England).</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1597</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 14 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06216</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16704</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S109735</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99845381</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99845381</idno>
            <idno type="VID">10278</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06216)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 10278)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 406:09)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The decree for tythes, to bee payde in London Anno M.D.LXXX.</title>
                  <author>City of London (England).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[16] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed [by James Roberts] for Gabriell Cawood,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>At London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1597.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Printer's name from STC.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A.</note>
                  <note>Running title reads: The decree for tithes, to be payd in London.</note>
                  <note>The last leaf is blank.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Tithes --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2010-01</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-02</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2010-04</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:10278:1"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 25 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:10278:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 25 -->
            <figure>
               <figDesc>decorative border</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <g ref="char:leaf">❧</g> THE <hi>DE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree for Tythes, to</hi> bee payde in Lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>don.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Anno M. D.</hi> LXXX.</p>
            <p>At London ¶ Printed for Ga<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>briell Cawood. 1597.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:10278:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 26 -->
            <pb facs="tcp:10278:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 26 -->
            <head>The Decree for Tithes, to bee payed in London.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>S touching the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of Tithes in the Citty of London, and the Liberties of the ſame: It is fully ordered and decréed by the moſt reuerend Father in God <hi>Thomas</hi> Archbiſhop of Can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terbury, Primate and Metropolitane of all England. <hi>Thomas</hi> Lord <hi>Wrio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>theſley,</hi> and Lord Chancelour of Eng<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>land. <hi>William</hi> Lord Saint <hi>Iohn,</hi> pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſident of the Kings Maieſties Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſell, and Lorde great Maiſter of hys Highnes houſhold, <hi>Iohn</hi> Lord <hi>Ruſſell,</hi> Lord priuie ſeale, <hi>Edward</hi> Earle of Hertford, Lord great Chamberlaine of England, <hi>Iohn viſcount Liſle</hi> high Admirall of England, <hi>Richard Liſter</hi> Knight chiefe Iuſtice of England, and <hi>Roger Cholrneley</hi> Knight, chiefe Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ron of his Graces Eſchequer, this
<pb facs="tcp:10278:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 27 -->
preſent twenty and foure day of Fe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bruary, <hi>Anno Domini ſecundum cur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſum &amp; computationem Eccleſié Ange<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>licanè milleſimo quingenteſimo qua<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>drageſimo quinto,</hi> according to the ſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tute in ſuch caſe lately prouided. That the Cittizens and inhabitants of the ſayd Citty of London and Liberties of the ſame, for the time beeing, ſhall yéerely without fraud or couin for euer pay their tithes to the Parſons, Vi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cars, and Curates of the ſayd Citty, and their ſucceſſours for the time be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, after the rate héereafter follow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, that is to wit, of euery tenne ſhil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lings rent by yeare of all and euerie houſe and houſes, ſhops, warehouſes, ſellers, and ſtables, and euery of them, within the ſaide Citty and Liberties of the ſame ſixtéene pence halfe penny. And of euery twenty ſhillings rent by yeare of all and euery ſuch houſe and houſes, ſhops, warehouſes, ſellers, and ſtables, and euery of them, with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in the ſaide Citty and Liberties, two ſhillings and nine pence: And ſo a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue the rent of twenty ſhillings by
<pb facs="tcp:10278:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 27 -->
yeare, aſcending from x.s<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. to x. s<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the rate aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>Item that where any leaſe is or ſhal be made of any dwelling houſe or hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, ſhops, warehouſes, ſellers, or ſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles, or of any of them, by fraud or co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uin, reſeruing leſſe rent then hath béen accuſtomed, or is, or that any ſuch leaſe ſhall be made without any rent reſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued vpon the ſame, by reaſon of anie fine or income payd before hand, or by anie other fraud or couin: That then in euery ſuch caſe the tenaunt or far<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mour, tenaunts or farmours thereof, ſhall pay for his or their tithes of the ſame, after the rate afore ſaid, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the quantitie of ſuch rent or rents, as the ſame houſe or houſes, ſhops, warehouſes, ſellers, or ſtables, or any of them were laſt letten for, without fraud or couin before the ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>king of ſuch leaſe.</p>
            <p>Item that euery owner or owners, inheritor or inheritors, of any dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling houſe or houſes, ſhopps, ware<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſes, ſellers, or ſtables, or anie of them within the ſaid Citty &amp; liberties,
<pb facs="tcp:10278:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
inhabiting or occupying the ſame him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe or themſelues, ſhall pay after ſuch rate of tithe as is aboue ſayde, after the quantity of ſuch yearely rent, as the ſame was laſt letten for, without fraud or couin.</p>
            <p>Item if any perſon or perſons haue taken, or héerafter ſhall take any meſe or manſion place by leaſe, and the ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ker or takers therof his or their execu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tors or aſſignes doth or ſhall inhabits in part therof, and haue or hath with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in viij. yeares laſt paſt before this or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der or héereafter will or ſhall let out the reſidue of the ſame: That then in ſuch caſe, the principall Farmour or Farmors or firſt taker or takers ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, his or their executors or aſſignes, ſhall pay his or their tithes after the rate aforeſaid, according to his or their quantity therin, and that his or theyr executors aſſigne or aſſignes, ſhall pay his or their tithes after the rate aboue ſayd, according to the quantity of his or their rent by yeare.</p>
            <p>And that if any perſon or perſons, haue or ſhall take diuers manſion hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes,
<pb facs="tcp:10278:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 28 -->
ſhops, warehouſes, ſellers, or ſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bles in one leaſe, and letteth, or ſhall let out one or more of the ſaid houſes, and kéepeth or ſhall kéepe one or more in his or their owne hands, and inha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>biteth or inhabiten in the ſame: That then the ſaid taker or takers, and his or their executors or aſſignes, ſhall pay his or their tithes after the rate aboue ſayd, according to the quantity of the yearele rent of ſuch manſion houſe or houſes retayned in his or their hands. And that his aſſigne or aſſignes of the reſidue of the ſayde manſion houſe or houſes ſhall pay his or their yearelie tithes after the rate aboue ſaid, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the quantity of their yearely rents.</p>
            <p>Item if ſuch Farmour or Farmors, or his or their aſſignes of any manſion houſes, warehouſes, ſhops, ſellers, or ſtables, hath at any time within eight yeares laſt paſt, or ſhall héereafter let ouer all the ſayd manſion houſe or hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes contayned in his or their leaſe to one perſon or to diuers perſons: That then the inhabitants leaſes or occupi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers
<pb facs="tcp:10278:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
of them, and of euery of them ſhal pay their tithes, after the rate of ſuch rents as the ſaid inhabitaunts, leaſes, or occupiers, and their aſſigne or aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignes, béen or ſhal be charged withal, without fraud or couin.</p>
            <p>Item if anie dwelling houſe with<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in eight yeares laſt paſt was or héere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhall be conuerted into a ware<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe, ſtorehouſe, or ſuch like, or if a warehouſe, ſtorehouſe, or ſuch lyke within the ſaide eigh<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> yeares, was or heerafter ſhalb<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> conuerted into a dwel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling houſe: That then the occupier or occupiers thereof ſhall pay tithes for the ſame, after the rate aboue declared of manſion houſ<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> rents.</p>
            <p>Item that where anie perſon ſhall demiſe anie Diehouſe or Brewhouſe with implements conuenient and ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſarie for dying or brewing, reſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uing a rent vpon the ſame, as well in reſpect of ſuch implementes, as in reſpect of ſuch Diehouſe or Brew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>houſe. That then the tenaunt ſhall pay his tithes, after ſuch rate as is a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boue ſaid, the third peny abated. And
<pb facs="tcp:10278:5"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 29 -->
that euery principall houſe or houſes with key or wharf, hailing any Crane or gibet belonging to the ſame, ſhall pay after like rate of their rents as is aforeſaid the third penny abated. And that other wharfes belonging to hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes, hauing no Crane or gibet, ſhal pay for their tithes as ſhalbe paid for man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion houſes in forme aforeſaid.</p>
            <p>Item that where any manſion houſe with a ſhoppe, ſtable, warehouſes, wharf, with Crane, timberyard, tein<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>teryard, or Garden belonging to the ſame, or as parcell of the ſame, is or ſhall be occupied together, that if the ſame be héereafter ſeuered or deuided, or at any time within viij. yeares laſt paſt were ſeuered or deuided: That then the farmour or farmours, occupi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, or occupiers, thereof ſhall pay ſuch tithes as aboue ſaid for ſuch ſhops, ſca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, warehouſe, wharfe, with Crane, timberyard, teinteryard, or garde<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> afore<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ſaid ſo ſeuered or deuided after y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> rate of their ſeuerall rents thervpon reſerued.</p>
            <p>Item that the ſayde Cittizens and inhabitaunts ſhall paye theyr tithes
<pb facs="tcp:10278:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
quarterly, that is to ſay, at the feaſt of Eaſter, the Natiuity of S. <hi>Iohn Bap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiſt,</hi> the feaſt of S. <hi>Michael</hi> the Arch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>angell, and the natiuity of our Lord by euen portions.</p>
            <p>Item that euery houſholder paying ten ſhillings rent or aboue, ſhall for him or her ſelfe be diſcharged of theyr foure offering dayes: but his wife, children, ſeruant, or others of their fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mily, taking their rights of the church at Eaſter, ſhall pay two pence for their foure offering dayes yéerely.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwayes, and it is decréed, that if any houſe or houſes, which hath béen, or heereafter ſhall be letten for tenne ſhillings rent by yéere or more, be or hath at any time within eyght yeares laſt paſſed, or héereafter ſhal be deuided and leaſed into ſmall parcels or members, yéelding leſſe yéerely rent then tenne ſhillings by yeare: That then the owner or owners, if hee or they dwell in any part of ſuch houſe, or elſe the principall leaſe or leaſes, if the owner or owners doe not dwell in ſome part of the ſame, ſhal from hence<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forth
<pb facs="tcp:10278:6"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 30 -->
pay for his or their tithes, after ſuch rate of rent as the ſame houſe was accuſtomed to be letten for before ſuch deuiſio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> or deuiding into parts or mem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bers. And the vnder Farmour and Farmours, leaſe and leaſes, to be diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>charged of all tithes, for ſuch ſmall parcels, parts, or members rented at leſſe yearely rents then ten ſhillings by yeare, without fraud or couin, pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing two pence a péece yéerely for their foure offering dayes.</p>
            <p>Prouided alway, and it is decréede, that for ſuch Gardens as appertayne not to any manſion houſe, and which any perſon or perſons, holdeth or ſhall hold in his or their hands for pleaſure, or to his owne vſe, that then the per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon ſo holding the ſame ſhall pay no tithes for the ſame. But if any perſon or perſons, which holdeth, and ſhall holde any ſuch Garden, contayning halfe an Acre or more, doth or ſhall make any yéerely profit therof by way of ſale: that then he or they ſhall pay tithes for the ſame, after ſuch rate of his rent, as is héerein firſt aboue ſpe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cified.</p>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:10278:7"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 31 -->Prouided alſo that if any ſuch Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dens now being of the quantity of half an Acre or more, be hereafter by fraud or couin deuided into any leſſe quantity or quantities, then to pay tithe, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the rate aboue ſaid.</p>
            <p>Prouided alway that this decrée ſhal not extend to the houſes of great men, or noble men, or noble women, kept in their owne hands, and not letten for any rent, which in time paſt hath pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed no tithes, ſo long as they ſhal ſo con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tinue vnletten, nor to any hals of crafts or companies ſo long as they be kept vnletten, ſo that the ſame hals in time paſt haue not vſed to pay any tithes.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwayes, and it is decréed, that this preſent order and decrée ſhall not in anie wiſe extende to binde or charge any ſheds, ſtables, ſellers, tim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber yards, no teynter yards, which were neuer parcell of any dwelling houſe, ne appertayning or belonging to any dwelling houſe, ne haue accu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtomed to pay any tithes: but that the ſaid Citizens &amp; inhabitants ſhal therof
<pb facs="tcp:10278:7"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 31 -->
be quiet of payment, of any tithes, as it hath béen vſed and accuſtomed.</p>
            <p>Prouided alſo, and it is decreede, that where leſſe ſumme then after the rate of ſixtéene pence halfpeny in the tenne ſhilings rent, or leſſe ſumme then two ſhillings and nine pence in the twen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty ſhillings rent, hath beene accuſto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med to be payd for tithes, that then in ſuch places, the ſaide Cittizens and in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>habitants ſhall pay but only after ſuch rate as hath been accuſtomed.</p>
            <p>Item, it is alſo decreede, that if any variance, controuerſie, or ſtrife doe or ſhall heereafter ariſe in the ſayd Cit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tie for no payment of any tithes: or if any variance or doubt ariſe vpon the true knowledge or diuiſion of any rent or tiths within the liberties of the ſaid Citty, or of any extent or aſſemblant thereof, or if anie doubt riſe vpon any other thing contayned within this de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree: that then vpon complaint made by the party greeued to y<hi rend="sup">e</hi> Mayre of the City of London for the time being, the ſayd Mayre by the aduiſe of counſaile ſhall call the ſayd parties before him,
<pb facs="tcp:10278:8"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 32 -->
and make a finall ende in the ſame, with coſts to be rewarded at the diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cretion of the ſayd Maire and his aſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtants, according to the intent and pur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poſe of this preſent decrée.</p>
            <p>And if that the ſaid Maire make not an end therof within two moneths af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter complaint to him made, or if any of the ſayd parties finde themſelues grée<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ued: That then the Lord Chaunceller of England for the time béeing vpon complaint to him made within thrée moneths then next following, ſhall make an ende of the ſame, with ſuch coſts to be rewarded as ſhalbe thought conuenient, according to the intent and purpoſe of this ſaid decree.</p>
            <p>Prouided alwayes, that if any per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons take any tenement for a leſſe rent then was accuſtomed to be letten for, by reaſon of any great ruine and decay, burning, or ſuch like occaſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons or miſ-fortunes: That then ſuch perſon or perſons, his executors or aſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſignes ſhall pay tithes onely after the rate of the rent reſerued in his or their leaſe, and none otherwiſe, as long as the ſame leaſe ſhall endure.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:10278:8"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 32 -->
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
